muuto.com 2019-04-20

# Privacy & Cookie Policy

This privacy policy sets out how we use and protect any information that you provide us with, by signing up to our newletter or by using this website. We are committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information for identification purposes, you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with our privacy statement. We may change the privacy policy occasionally by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes that have been made. 

  * INTRODUCTION

  * WHAT WE COLLECT AND WHY

  * WHAT WE DO WITH THE INFORMATION WE GATHER 

  * YOUR RIGHTS 

  * LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES 

  * PROTECTION OF PRIVATE INFORMATION 

  * COOKIES

  * CONTACT

  * INTRODUCTION

It is important for Muuto to protect and respect your privacy, and it is our  
goal to keep and process your personal data securely and appropriately.  
In our privacy policy you can read the terms for how we process your   
personal data and the rights you have when using our website. You can find  
the extensive policy by navigating the left side menu. 

You will always be able to find our privacy policy on this page, and it will be  
updated whenever there are relevant changes.

This is version 1.0 of Muutos Privacy Policy dated 11th of May 2018.

If you have any questions or comments regarding our privacy policy  
please contact us at [customercare@muuto.com](https://muuto.com/contact#customer-care).

  * WHAT WE COLLECT AND WHY

WHAT IS PERSONAL DATA:

Personal data is data that can identify a person such as name, address,  
email, phone number, picture and IP-address. 

MUUTO COLLECTS PERSONAL DATA:

When you visit muuto.com, we automatically collect information about  
your use of the website, e.g. the browser you are using, search words  
you have used on the website, your IP-adress and network location,  
and information about how you access our website. We collect this in order to optimize the  
user experience and functionality of the website. 

If you as a wholesale or contract customer buy products from Muuto, or if  
you contact [customercare@muuto.com](https://muuto.com/contact#customer-care), we collect the data you yourself provide,  
e.g. name, adress, company, mail, phone number, payment method, info on the  
products you have bought and might have returned, and shipping information. 

When you sign up to our newsletter (Private, Contract Dealer or Wholesale) we  
collect the information provided when signing up, being your name, mail and country. 

  * WHAT WE DO WITH THE INFORMATION WE GATHER 

WE COLLECT AND USE DATA FOR DIFFERENT PURPOSES:

The purpose of collecting and using your personal information can be divided into the two following categories:

1\. There is some personal data that we need to know about you, in order to deliver our service to you, e.g. identification and contact information like your name, your adress or mail. We have to follow the current legislations at all times and therefore register and save relevant personal data. Thereby complying with tax and book keeping legislations. 

2\. There is some personal data that we would like to know about you in order to improve our services, communication and marketing so we can offer you the best and most relevant information and service. 

DELETION OF PERSONAL DATA:

Your personal data will be deleted when it is no longer relevant for the initial purpose for why it was collected, processed and saved. 

SHARING OF PERSONAL DATA:

We do not sell, publish or in any other way forward your personal data to others, unless:  
\- It is necessary in order to deliver our service to you.  
\- It is necessary in order to comply with legislation.  
\- You have given us your concent to do so.  
\- It is part of a collaboration with data processers, both in and outside of EU/EØS. 

  * YOUR RIGHTS 

To get transparency about how we handle your personal information, we hereby inform you of your rights. 

RIGHT TO ACCESS:

You are at any time entitled to get access to any information we have regarding you, what our purposes with the registration is and from where we have obtained the information. You have the right to have get a copy of the personal data we have on you. If you want a copy of your personal data, you need to send a written requests to [customercare@muuto.com](https://muuto.com/contact#customer-care). You can be asked to document, that you are who you claim to be. 

RIGHT TO CORRECTION:

You have the right to get incorrect information about you corrected. If you find that Muuto holds incorrect information about you, you are always welcome to write us an email so we can correct the information. 

RIGHT TO DELETION:

You have the right to get all or some of your personal information deleted by us, if it does not conflict with another Danish law. 

RIGHT TO LIMIT HANDLING OF PERSONAL DATA:

You have the right to ask us to limit the handling of your personal data. 

RIGHT TO OPPOSE:

You have the right to oppose to our treatment of your personal data, in regards to direct marketing and profiling. 

RIGHT TO REVOKE:

You have the right to revoke your concent. If you wish to revoke your concent, please contact us at [customercare@muuto.com](https://muuto.com/contact#customer-care). 

RIGHT TO COMPLAIN:

You have the right to make a complaint to Datatilsynet, Borgergade 28, 5, 1300 København K, about how we handle your personal data. Complaints can be given by email to dt@datatilsynet.dk or by phone [+45 33 19 32 00](tel:+45 33 19 32 00). 

  * LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES 

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information, which you provide whilst visiting such sites and this privacy statement does not govern such sites. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question. 

  * PROTECTION OF PRIVATE INFORMATION 

We are totally committed to protecting the privacy of our website visitors and customers. Muuto A/S do not sell, share or transfer your personal information to any outside parties other than our third party processors. For the sole purpose of operating our business, suppliers or third party processors (such as credit card companies, customer service providers and shipping companies) may process your information, but only to the extent that it is needed to assist the Muuto business. 

  * COOKIES

When you visit [muuto.com](https://muuto.com/) we collect information about your activities on our website (for example by using cookies). A cookie is a small data file placed on your computer’s hard drive containing information about which parts of our website you have visited. We use cookies to personalise your online experience and to collect statistical data for the purpose of improving the buying experience on the website. Cookies are reliable files and they cannot execute program code, transmit viruses or be used to collect information about what you otherwise may use your computer for. We do not use cookies to store or collect personal information. 

You are free to decline the use of cookies. Most web browsers permits you to delete or block cookies and to warn you and ask for your consent before cookies are stored. You can find help in your browser on how to set your browser to handle and possibly block cookies. If you do not wish to use cookies when visiting our online store this may affect your shopping experience, as we among other things use cookies to keep your shopping cart updated. The use of cookies is also necessary if you want to be able to place an order. 

HOW DO WE USE COOKIES?

We use cookies for the following primary purposes; functionality, web statistics, sales and advertising. We use the functional cookies to ensure that our online store is functioning as intended, which among other things includes that you are able to add items to your shopping cart, place an order, etc. We do not store any personal information and the cookies expire and no longer have any effect once you have closed your browser. 

WHAT DO WE USE COOKIES FOR?

We use services from Google (Google Analytics) to collect web statistics. Cookies from this provider among other things allow us to see which pages are visited, where the traffic comes from, etc. We use the information to measure and improve the user experience on our website and to follow up on sales and ad campaigns. 

Additionally we use partners that help us to keep track of user activities, profitability of online marketing and to deliver targeted online ads when you visit other websites. These services may use third part cookies provided by our partners. 

  * CONTACT

If you have any questions or comments regarding our privacy policy  
please contact us at [customercare@muuto.com](https://muuto.com/contact#customer-care)

## STORIES

[

### NEWS

](https://muuto.com/news)

Explore our latest new perspectives on Scandinavian design, including the Pebble Rug, Beam Lamp, Fiber Lounge Chair, Outline Highback Sofa and more.

[

### EMBRACINGLY SIMPLE:   
FIBER LOUNGE CHAIR

](https://muuto.com/stories/embracingly-simple-fiber-lounge-chair)

Adding a new chapter to the iconic Fiber Chair family is the Fiber Lounge Chair—a design with a lightly hovering appearance and extensive comfort that invites the user in for a relaxed and embracing seat.

[

### UNDERSTATED EXPRESSIONS: LINEAR STEEL SERIES

](https://muuto.com/stories/understated-expressions-linear-steel-series)

The Linear Steel Series brings new perspectives to modern outdoor furniture through its straight lines alongside the folded edges, halfcircular intersecting legs and small spacing for easy removal of water.

## Functional cookies (18)

**Cookie name**

**Lifetime**

**Application**

**Description / Application**

PHPSESSID

Until the browser closes.

muuto.com

Used to store session data.

SNS

Until the browser closes.

muuto.com

form_key

Until the browser closes.

muuto.com

Preventing Cross-Site Request Forgery.

mage-cache-sessid

Until the browser closes.

muuto.com

The value of this cookie triggers the cleanup of local cache storage. When the cookie is removed by the backend application, the Admin cleans up local storage, and sets the cookie value to “true.”

mage-cache-storage

Until the browser closes.

muuto.com

Local storage of visitor-specific content that enables ecommerce functions.

mage-cache-storage-section-invalidation

Until the browser closes.

muuto.com

Forces local storage of specific content sections that should be invalidated.

mage-messages

1 year

muuto.com

Tracks error messages and other notifications that are shown to the user, such as the cookie consent message, and various error messages, The message is deleted from the cookie after it is shown to the shopper.

mage-translation-file-version

Until the browser closes.

muuto.com

Facilitates translation of content to other languages.

mage-translation-storage

Until the browser closes.

muuto.com

Facilitates translation of content to other languages.

private_content_version

Until the browser closes.

muuto.com

Used for displaying user informations.

section_data_ids

Until the browser closes.

muuto.com

Stores info for cache-invalidation

cookies

1 month

muuto.com

Saves info about accepted cookies

functional_cookie_accepted

1 month

muuto.com

Saves info about accepted cookies

some_cookie_accepted

1 month

muuto.com

Saves info about accepted cookies

engine_cookie_accepted

1 month

muuto.com

Saves info about accepted cookies

searchsuiteautocomplete

Until the browser closes.

muuto.com

Stores information about user searches.

## Social media and advertisements (12)

**Cookie name**

**Lifetime**

**Application**

**Description / Application**

_ga

2 year

muuto.com

Used for tracking usage patterns. (Google Analytics)

_gid

24 hours

muuto.com

Used for tracking usage patterns. (Google Analytics)

SID

2 years

Google

Used to coordinate the ads you view on different devices.

SSID

2 years

Google

Used to coordinate the ads you view on different devices.

SIDCC

3 months

Google

Used to coordinate the ads you view on different devices.

SAPISID

2 years

Google

Saves data associated with google maps.

NID

6 months

Google

Used to remember the user's preferences such as: language.

HSID

2 years

Google

Used to coordinate the ads you view on different devices.

APISID

2 years

Google

Saves data associated with google maps.

1p_JAR

2 months

Google

Used to collect user statistics.

_pk_id.****

2 year

muuto.com

Used for tracking usage patterns. (Piwik)

_pk_ses.****

24 hours

muuto.com

Used for tracking usage patterns. (Piwik)

fr

3 months

Facebook

Used for advertising on facebook
